It's about crime. It's about payback. It's about survival.
Set It Off is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by F. Gary Gray.
Four inner-city Black women, determined to end their constant struggle,
decide to live by one rule — get what you want or die trying.
So the four women take back their lives and take out some banks in the process.
Stony, played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
Cleo, played by Queen Latifah.
Frankie, played by Vivica A. Fox.
Tisean, played by Kimberly Elise.
Keith, played by Blair Underwood.
Detective Strode, played by John C. McGinley.
Set It Off is a 1996 American crime action film directed by F.
Gary Gray and written by Kate Lanier and Takashi Bufford.
The film stars Jada Pinkett, Queen Latifah, Vivica A.
Fox, and Kimberly Elise (in her film acting debut).
It follows four close friends in Los Angeles, California, who plan to execute a bank robbery—each
doing so for different reasons—to achieve better for themselves and their families.
The film was a box office success, grossing over $41
million against a budget of $9 million.
The film earned positive reviews from critics, who praised the characters, music and performances of the cast
(particularly that of Pinkett and Latifah), as well as the chemistry of the four leading actresses.
The soundtrack was a commercial success, peaking at number four on the
Billboard 200 and number three on the Top R&B/Hip-Hop Albums.
Additionally, the singles "Set It Off", "Don't Let Go (Love)", "Days of Our
Livez", "Angel", "Come On", "Let It Go" and "Missing You" each charted.
The film explores themes of single parent, bank robber,
last chance, heist, los angeles, california.
The tone is uplifting and emotional and thought_provoking.